Guide to the South Asian Pamphlets Collection, 1920-2005 (bulk 1950-2000) RL.01235
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
South Asian Pamphlets collection
1920-2005 (bulk 1950-2000)
1950-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Perkins Library. South Asian Studies
RL.01235
200 Linear Feet
The South Asian Pamphlets Collection spans the years 1920-2005, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1950s to the 1990s, and with only a few items from the 1920s-1940s. It is arranged in the following categories by country of publication: Afghanistan, Bangladesh, India, Nepal, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka. The largest group houses publications from India (177 boxes), followed by Pakistan (58 boxes). Topics commonly covered in each country series include but are not limited to agriculture, arts, defense, economic development, education, ethnic or cultural conflict, industry and commerce, international relations, politics and government, population issues, religion and philosophy, rural development, tourism, and the status of women. While the majority of the pamphlets were published by organizations and agencies and do not list individual authors' names, there are also pamphlets with individual authors listed.
Approximately 7500 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The publications in the South Asian Pamphlets Collection were received by Duke University's Perkins Library over four decades, roughly from 1960-1990, through the Library of Congress South Asia Cooperative Acquisition Program (SACAP), formerly called the "PL-480 Program."
Collection Overview
The South Asian Pamphlets Collection spans the years 1920-2005, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1950s to the 1990s, and with only a few items from the 1920s-1940s. The publications were received by Duke University's Perkins Library over four decades, roughly from 1960-1990, through the Library of Congress South Asia Cooperative Acquisition Program (SACAP), formerly called the "PL-480 Program," and are arranged according to their country of publication: Afghanistan, Bangladesh, India, Nepal, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka. The pamphlets are all published in the English language. The largest group houses publications from India (177 boxes), followed by Pakistan (58 boxes), Bangladesh (15 boxes), and Nepal (8 boxes). For the smallest groupings of Afghanistan and Sri Lanka, the pamphlets are organized alphabetically by title without any further subdivisions. For the larger country series, the pamphlets are arranged by topical headings, in alphabetical order, and within, alphabetically by title. Each country series is followed by a more detailed description of its contents; each topical division is also followed by a description which includes the number of boxes and number of items in that subdivision.
While the majority of the pamphlets were published by organizations and agencies and do not list individual authors' names, there are also pamphlets with individual authors listed. Topical divisions common to the larger country series include but are not limited to Agriculture, Arts, Economic Development, Education, Industry and Commerce, International Relations, Politics and Government, Religion and Philosophy, Rural Development, Tourism, and Women. Many of the publications across the entire collection discuss ethnic and political conflict, as well as the effects of wars, poverty, and mass education, and issues regarding Islam and other religious traditions. Particular countries may have unique topical headings. In the case of India, each major Indian political party has its own subdivision under the larger Political Parties series; there is also a section for biographical works, and one for works on libraries and museums, and a division was also established to house pamphlets related to Kashmir.
For undated pamphlets, every effort was made to establish an approximate year or decade of publication; this is indicated by a question mark following the date. Where there is no information on place of publication, the notation [n.p.] is used. In some cases there is a descriptive note below the entry that adds information about the item such as publication data, commemorative headings, inscriptions, and other contextual information. For more information on each country and its subdivisions, see the listings that follow.
India -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Agriculture -- India; Arts -- India; Economic development -- India; Education -- India -- History; Kashmir -- History; Economic development -- Sri Lanka; Women -- India -- 20th century; Agriculture -- Sri Lanka; India -- International relations; Sri Lanka -- Politics and government -- 20th century; India -- Religion; Pakistan -- Social conditions -- 20th century; Education -- Bangladesh -- History; Pakistan -- Political parties; Nepal -- History -- 20th century; Tourism -- Nepal -- History; Arts -- Bangladesh; Pakistan -- History -- 20th century; Economic development -- Bangladesh; Bangladesh -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Agriculture -- Nepal; Economic development -- Nepal; Agriculture -- Bangladesh; Bangladesh -- History -- 20th century; Nepal -- Social conditions -- 20th century; Bangladesh -- Social conditions -- 20th century; Nepal -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Economic development -- Afghanistan; Sri Lanka -- History -- 20th century; Refugees -- Afghanistan; Sri Lanka -- Social conditions -- 20th century; Afghanistan -- Social conditions -- 20th century; Education -- Pakistan -- History; Afghanistan -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Women -- Pakistan -- 20th century; India -- History -- 20th century; Arts -- Pakistan; Afghanistan -- History -- 20th century; Economic development -- Pakistan; India -- Political parties; Pakistan -- Politics and government -- 20th century; India -- Social conditions -- 20th century; Agriculture -- Pakistan
- Afghanistan Pamphlets, 1970s-1993, 2 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  These 19 pamphlets were published by Afghan individuals and institutional offices in exile in Pakistan during the Soviet occupation of Afghanistan. Topics covered include the status of Afghan refugees; Pakistan's foreign policy; U.N. resolutions; country reports; the Soviet occupation and war in Afghanistan; foreign aid; armed responses to the Soviet aggressions; and the National Islamic Front of Afghanistan. Publications include official decrees of the Democratic Republic of Afghanistan, a gazetteer, and news reports from Afghani and foreign media.
  For undated pamphlets, every effort was made to establish an approximate year or decade of publication; this is indicated by a question mark following the date. In cases where there is no place of publication information, the notation [n.p.] is used. In some cases there is a descriptive note below the entry that adds information about the item such as publication data, commemorative headings, inscriptions, and other contextual information.
  - Afghanistan. Karmal, Babrak. India: New Delhi, New Age Printing Press, 1982. (Box AF-1)
    "On the occasion of the 4th anniversary of the April Revolution."
  - Afghanistan Info. Comite Suisse de soutien au peuple afghan. Switzerland: Neuchatel, 1989. (Box AF-1)
    Mostly in French with some German.
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan. Hussain, Syed Shabbir. Pakistan: [n.p.], [no publisher], 1980? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan. Pakistan: Islamabad, Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, 1987. (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Azakhel Refugees Camp. Commissionerate Of Afghan Refugees, N.W.F.P. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1981? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Bada Ber Refugees Camp. Commissionerate Of Afghan Refugees, N.W.F.P. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1981? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Bara Kai Refugees Camp. Commissionerate Of Afghan Refugees, N.W.F.P. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1981? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Gandaf Refugees Camp. Commissionerate Of Afghan Refugees, N.W.F.P. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1981? (Box AF-1)
    The oldest camp.
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Jalozai Refugees Camp. Commissionerate Of Afghan Refugees, N.W.F.P. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1981? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Kacha Garhi Refugee Camp. Commissionerate Of Afghan Refugees, N.W.F.P. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1981? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Nasir Bagh Refugee Camp. Pakistan: Peshawar, Afghan Refugees Commissionerate, N.W.P.F., 1982? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Some Facts. Pakistan: Islamabad, Chief Commissioner for Afghan Refugees, Government of Pakistan, 1982? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghan Refugees in Pakistan: Tindo Refugees Camp. Commissionerate Of Afghan Refugees, N.W.F.P. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1981? (Box AF-1)
  - Afghanistan Report. The Institute of Strategic Studies. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1987. (Box AF-1)
    No. 41, August 1987.
  - Afghanistan's National Fatherland Front. Communist Party of India. India: New Delhi, 1981. (Box AF-1)
    Documents of the Founding Congress of Afghanistan's National Fatherland Front, Kabul, 15-16 June 1981.
  - Armed Intervention in Afghanistan. Pakistan:Government of Pakistan, Ministry of Information & Broadcasting, Directorate of Films and Publications,1980. (Box AF-1)
    View from Pakistan.
  - Call for Immediate Withdrawal of Foreign Troops from Afghanistan. Pakistan Publications. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1984? (Box AF-1)
    6th U.N. Resolution.
  - Call for Immediate Withdrawal of Foreign Troops from Afghanistan. Pakistan. Ministry of Information & Broadcasting. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1986. (Box AF-1)
    7th U.N. Resolution.
  - Challenge from the North. Pakistan:Islamabad, Institute of Policy Studies, 197-? (Box AF-1)
    Speech of Mr. Agha Shahi, Former Foreign Minister of Pakistan, to the Launching Ceremony of Afghanistan Crisis: Implications and Options for Muslim World, Iran and Pakistan.
  - Declaration of the Afghan National Liberation Front, The. Afghan National Liberation Front. [Pakistan]: [n.p.], 197-? (Box AF-1)
    A photocopy of the declaration which was most likely published in Pakistan.
  - Decrees of the Democratic Republic of Afghanistan. Rahban, Hadi. Afghanistan: [Kabul?], Ministry of Information and Culture, 197-? (Box AF-1)
  - Economic Motives of Russian Aggression on Afghanistan. Jamiat-e-Islami Afghanistan. Afghanistan: Peshawar, 1981. (Box AF-1)
  - Education for Afghan Refugee Children. Pakistan: Peshawar, N.W.P.F., 1985. (Box AF-1)
  - Front, The/Mahaz. National Islamic Front of Afghanistan. Afghanistan: Peshawar, 1988. (Box AF-1)
    Vol. 1, No. 6; March, April 1988.
  - Humanitarian Assistance Programme for Afghan Refugees in Pakistan. Pakistan: [Islamabad], Chief Commissionerate for Afghan Refugees, Government of Pakistan, 1983. (Box AF-1)
  - India's Views on the Afghan Situation. India. Ministry of External Affairs. India: New Delhi, 1981. (Box AF-1)
  - Jihad Rays, The. Cultural Committee of the Islamic Unity of the Afghan Mujahideen. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1985. (Box AF-1)
    The Afghan Muslim People against the Red Imperialism; Vol. IV No. 1-2, Jan. - Feb. 1985.
  - Long Wait, The: Afghan Refugees in Pakistan. Hussain, Syed Shabbir. Pakistan: Islamabad, Kamran Pub. House, 1982. (Box AF-2)
  - Manifesto of the National Islamic Front of Afghanistan. National Islamic Front of Afghanistan. Afghanistan: [Kabul?], 198-? (Box AF-2)
  - Memorandum on Relief Assistance for Afghan Refugees in Pakistan, 1985-86. Pakistan. States and Frontier Regions Division. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1985. (Box AF-2)
  - Memorandum on Relief Assistance for Afghan Refugees in Pakistan, 1993-94. Islamabad, States and Frontier Regions Divisions. Pakistan: Islamabad, Government of Pakistan, 1993. (Box AF-2)
  - Monthly Bulletin. Afghan Information Centre. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1983. (Box AF-2)
    No. 22, January 1983.
  - Monthly Bulletin. Afghan Information Centre. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1983. (Box AF-2)
    No. 26, May 1983.
  - Monthly Bulletin. Afghan Information Centre. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1986. (Box AF-2)
    No. 61, April 1986.
  - Our Stand on War and Peace in Afghanistan. Press and Information Department, Political Committee. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1986? (Box AF-2)
  - Overview of NGO Assistance: Afghan Programmes 1990-1991. Agency Coordinating Body for Afghan Relief. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1992. (Box AF-2)
  - Provisional Gazetteer of Afghanistan: Reissued for Administrative Structure and Numbering. Afghanistan: Baghlan, 197-? (Box AF-2)
  - Relief Work for Afghan Refugees. Afghan Refugees Commissionerate. Pakistan: Peshawar, Public Relations Cell, 1982? (Box AF-2)
  - Resistance in Afghanistan: Mujahideen Leaders' Interview. Siddiqi, A. R. Afghanistan: Karachi, Defence Journal, 1981? (Box AF-2)
  - Revolutionary Association of the Women of Afghanistan. RAWA. Pakistan: Quetta, 198-? (Box AF-2)
  - Situation in Afghanistan: UN Call for Withdrawal of Foreign Troops. Pakistan Publications. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1983? (Box AF-2)
    5th UN Resolution.
  - U.N. Reiterates Call: Withdraw Troops from Afghanistan. Pakistan Publications. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1980. (Box AF-2)
  - U.N.'s Call: Total Withdrawal from Afghanistan. Pakistan Foreign Affairs Advisor's Address. Shahi, Agha. Pakistan: Islamabad, Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, 1980. (Box AF-2)
  - U.N. Total Withdrawal of Foreign Troops: Situation in Afghanistan: Implications for International Peace. Pakistan. Ministry of Information & Broadcasting. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1983. (Box AF-2)
    4th UN Resolution - Call for.
  - UNICEF Assistance to Afghan Refugees in Pakistan. United Nations Children's Fund. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1984. (Box AF-2)
  - Union Aid for Afghan Refugees (U.A.A.R) Peshawar-Pakistan: Report of Activities for the Year 1982. Pakistan: 1982. (Box AF-2)
  - Weekly News. Hezb-i-Islami Afghanistan. Pakistan: Peshawar, 1987. (Box AF-2)
  - Withdraw Troops from Afghanistan. Pakistan. Ministry of Information & Broadcasting. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1981. (Box AF-2)
  - World Press Reaction: Soviet Intervention in Afghanistan. Pakistan Forum. Pakistan: Islamabad, 1980? (Box AF-2)
- Bangladesh Pamphlets, 1957-2002, 15 boxes
  Publications are subdivided into the following groupings, described fully below each heading: Agriculture, Arts, Economics and Public Policy, Education, Industry and Commerce, International Relations, Law, Miscellaneous Subjects, Politics and Government, Population and Birth Control, Rural Development, and Tourism.
  - Agriculture, 1963-1987, 1 box
    The nine pamphlets in this section were published by official government agencies and individuals between 1963 and 1987. Subject areas include agricultural statistics, specific crops, cooperative farming, livestock and mechanization and modernization.
    - Accelerated Rice Research Program for East Pakistan in Cooperation with the International Rice Research Institute (IRRI). McClung, A. Colin. Bangladesh: Dacca, Accelerated Rice Research Program, 1965. (Box BA-1)
    - Agricultural Statistics of East Pakistan for the Year 1952-53. East Pakistan. Directorate of Agriculture. Bangladesh: Dacca, 1963. (Box BA-1)
    - Agriculture of East Pakistan. Pakistan: Islamabad, The Ford Foundation, 1970. (Box BA-1)
      Selected Tables.
    - Assessment of Quantitative Losses of Aus Paddy during Post-harvest Operations in Wet Season of Mymensingh District. Anwarul Karim, A. M. Bangladesh: Mymensingh, Bangladesh Agricultural University, 1982. (Box BA-1)
    - Boro Crop Survey in Comilla Kotwali Thana, 1966-67. Safiullah, M. Pakistan: Comilla, Pakistan Academy for Rural Development, 1968. (Box BA-1)
    - BR-3: A New Rice Cultivar of Bangladesh. Bangladesh Rice Research Institute. Bangladesh: Dacca, 1974? (Box BA-1)
    - Comilla Co-operative Cold Storage. Rahman, Mahmoodur. Rural Business Management. Pakistan: Comilla, Pakistan Academy For Rural Development, The Director, 1967. (Box BA-1)
    - Comments on: East Pakistan's Accelerated Rice research Program in cooperation With The International Rice Research Institute. Chandler, Robert F. Pakistan: Karachi, The Ford Foundation, 1966. (Box BA-1)
      This paper contains observations from a tour of East Pakistan rice research station, September 20-24, 1966. The conclusions are summarized.
    - Cooperative Farming in Comilla. Karim, Rezaul. Bangladesh: Comilla, Pakistan Academy for Rural Development, 1970. (Box BA-1)
    - Farm Management Survey Report On Chittagong Project. Pakistan. Food And Agriculture Division. Pakistan: Islamabad, Planning Unit, 1970. (Box BA-1)
      Farm Management Research In Pakistan.
    - Fertilizer. East Pakistan Agricultural Development Corporation. Pakistan: Dacca, Public Relations Division, 1970? (Box BA-1)
    - Increasing and Diversifying: Food Production in East Pakistan. Bradfield, Richard.Pakistan: Dacca, Agricultural Research Institute, 1967. (Box BA-1)
    - Live-stock Population: A Survey in Comilla Kotwali and Chandina Thanas. Rahman, Mahmoodur. Bangladesh: Comilla, Pakistan Academy for Rural Development, 1968. (Box BA-1)
    - Progress Report on: Accelerated Rice Research Program of East Pakistan in Cooperation with the International Rice Research Institute. Chandler, Robert F. Bangladesh: Dacca, The Ford Foundation, 1966. (Box BA-1)
    - Progress Report on: Accelerated Rice Research Program of East Pakistan, January-August 1966. Alim, A., H. Zaman and L. P. V. Johnson. Bangladesh: Dacca, Accelerated Rice Research Program, 1966. (Box BA-1)
    - Season and Crop Report of East Pakistan for the Year, 1959-60. East Pakistan. Directorate of Agriculture. Bangladesh: Dacca, 1965. (Box BA-1)
    - Studies on Nitrogen Efficiency Improvement for Wheat. Hafizar Rahman, A. F. M. Bangladesh: Dacca, Bangladesh Soil Fertility and Soil Testing Institute, 197-? (Box BA-1)
    - Social Constraints of Agricultural Mechanization and Modernization. Hossain, Anwar. Bangladesh: Dhaka, Institute of Business Administration, University of Dhaka, 1987. (Box BA-1)
    - Study on the Present Situation of Vegetable-Growing in East Pakistan. Ahmad, Kamaluddin. Bangladesh: Dacca, Agricultural Research Institute, 1968. (Box BA-1)
  - Arts, 1979-1987, 1 box
    The ten pamphlets in this section were published by official government agencies and individuals discuss art exhibitions, museums, academies, and the Film Development Corporation (FDC).
    - Art Exhibition of Nargis Mannan. Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy. Bangladesh: [Dhaka], 1987. (Box BA-2)
      Catalog for an exhibition held October 17-23, 1987.
    - Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy. Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy. Bangladesh: Dacca, 1980? (Box BA-2)
    - Exhibition of Arts, August 18-25, 1981. Rashid, Harun ur. Bangladesh: [Dhaka], Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy, 1981? (Box BA-2)
    - Exhibition of Paintings, February 20 - March 1, 1981. Kibria, Asma. Bangladesh: [Dhaka], Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy, 1981? (Box BA-2)
    - FDC: 25 Silver Jubilee, 1983. Bangladesh Film Development Corporation.Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1983. (Box BA-2)
    - First National Crafts Exhibition of NGOs 1987, The. Association of Development Agencies in Bangladesh. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1987. (Box BA-2)
    - First National Exhibition of Appropriate Technologies by NGOs 1987, The. Association of Development Agencies in Bangladesh. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1987. (Box BA-2)
    - Museum Guide: Folk Art Museum, Sonargaon. Bangladesh Folk Art & Crafts Foundation. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 197-? (Box BA-2)
    - Painting and Sculpture Exhibition of Farida Azman, Alok Roy, Swapan Chowdhury, Hashi Chakraborty, K. M. Abdul Qayyum, Ratan Majumdar, A. K. M. Alamgir, Chandra Shekhar Dey, Mansurul Karim, Hamiduzzaman Khan, Abdus Satter. Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1979? (Box BA-2)
    - Statement By East Pakistan Scholars and Artists. Pakistan. Department of Films and Publications. Pakistan: Karachi, 1971. (Box BA-2)
  - Economics and Public Policy, 1965-1998, 2 boxes
    Published by official government agencies and individuals, these 34 pamphlets cover topics such as international economic relations, trade agreements, economic research, economic policy, economic aid, environmental improvement projects, land reforms, labor, the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD), jute policies, charity, and systems of barter.
    - Bangladesh and the Proposed International Agreement on Tea: A Position Paper. Chowdhury, Nuimuddin. Bangladesh: Dacca, Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies, 1976. (Box BA-3)
      A paper presented at the National Seminar on "The New International Economic Order & UNCTAD IV" held at BIDS, March 1976.
    - Bangladesh: Unyielding Efforts. Ahmed, Salehuddin. Bangladesh: Dhaka, Ministry of Information, 1987. (Box BA-3)
    - Barter Trade Between Bangladesh and East European Countries: Some Observations. Ghafur, Abdul. Bangladesh: Dacca, Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies, 1976. (Box BA-3)
    - Bureau of Economic Research, The. University of Dacca.Bangladesh: Dacca, 1974. (Box BA-3)
      A brochure on its activities.
    - Collective Bargaining: Reflections on Asian Experience. Thiagarajah, R. Bangladesh: Dacca, 1981. (Box BA-3)
      National Tripartite Labour Conference, Dacca, December 21-22, 1981.
    - Comparative Advantage and Exports of Manufactures: Policy Implications for Bangladesh. Mahfuzur Rahman, A. H. M. Bangladesh: [n.p.], [The Author?], 1973. (Box BA-3)
    - CPD-UNRISD Dialogue on Gender Issues in Export-Based Industrialization in Bangladesh, A. Centre for Policy Dialogue. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1995. (Box BA-3)
      CPD Dialogue Report No. 11, 27-28 October 1995, Dhaka.
    - Dialogue Report on the State of the Bangladesh Economy in the Financial Year 1997-98. Centre for Policy Dialogue. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1998. (Box BA-3)
      CPD Dialogue Report No. 17, 9 May 1998.
    - East Pakistan Capital Gains Tax Rules, The. Finance Department. Pakistan: Dacca, Finance Department, 1968. (Box BA-3)
    - East Pakistan Hotel Tax Rules, The. Finance Department. Pakistan: Dacca, Finance Department, 1967. (Box BA-3)
    - Enfants du Monde: Bangladesh. Enfants du Monde. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 199-? (Box BA-3)
    - Environmental Consequences of Export Oriented Shrimp Culture in Bangladesh: Reforms and Changes: A Workshop Report. Centre for Policy Dialogue. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1998. (Box BA-3)
      CPD Dialogue Report No. 18, October 1998.
    - Environmental Improvement Project: Chittagong: 1988-1997. Chittagong City Corporation. Bangladesh: Chittagong, 1998? (Box BA-3)
    - Enivronmental Imporvement Project: Dhaka. 1988-1997. Dhaka City Corporation. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1998? (Box BA-3)
    - Financial Indicators Bangladesh. Bangladesh Centre for Advanced Studies.Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1994. (Box BA-3)
      Vol. 4, Issue 4.
    - Foreign Capital Inflow: Some Observations. Alamgir, Mohiuddin. Bangladesh: Dacca, Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies, 1976. (Box BA-3)
    - Foundation-stone Laying Ceremony of the NIPA Building. Chaudhuri, S. B. Bangladesh: Dacca, National Institute of Public Administration, 1965. (Box BA-3)
      Address given on January 26, 1965.
    - Integrated Programme for Commodities. Chowdhury, M. Nurun Nabi. Bangladesh: Dacca, Ministry of Commerce & Foreign Trade, 1975? (Box BA-3)
    - Land Reforms. Bangladesh. Ministry of Information. Bangladesh: Dhaka, 1990. (Box BA-3)
    - New International Economic Order and UNCTAD IV, The. Rahman, S. H., ed. Bangladesh: Dacca, Bangladesh National Seminar, 1976. (Box BA-4)
    - NIPA Calendar, 1973-78. National Institute of Public Administration. Bangladesh: Dacca, 1978. (Box BA-4)
    - Post-devaluation Jute Policy. Bennathan, Esra and Sultan Hafeez Rahman. Bangladesh: Dacca, Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies, 1976. (Box BA-4)